We just finished calling a method and passing in inputs.
刚刚我们完成了调用方法和传递参数
&gt;&gt; Oh wait.
哦 等等
Are you referring to passing in quality to what was it,
你刚刚提起的那个传递参数是什么
the calculate price method?
calculatePrice 方法？
&gt;&gt; Exactly.
确实是
And now we want to get a return value out of it.
现在我们想从这个方法中得到一个返回值
&gt;&gt; I love return values.
我喜欢返回值
&gt;&gt; [LAUGH] &gt;&gt; What is it going to be?
将会发生什么?
I think a price?
我认为是一个价格
Because it's the calculate price method.
因为它是一个计算价格的方法
&gt;&gt; Yeah the total order price is going to be the return value.
是的 返回值是总价
&gt;&gt; Okay, let's do that!
好的 我们行动吧
&gt;&gt; Okay. Do you need a fork?
好的 你需要一个叉子吗？
&gt;&gt; Do I?
我需要吗？
&gt;&gt; In Java, the output of a method is known as a return value.
在 Java 中方法的输出被认为是一个返回值
In code samples, you may have seen the word return inside the method, or
在代码的例子 你可能注意到方法里
seen the word return In the comment above it.
或看到注释中的 return
Let's look up more information about the return values for methods.
让我们看一下更多关于方法返回值的信息
I'm going to do a Google search for Java method return value.
我将 Google 查一下 java method return value
The first link looks good.
第一个链接看起来不错
This article talks about returning a value from a method.
这篇文章介绍了方法的返回值
It says that a method is finished being executed
它说一个方法结束执行
when we've completed all statements in the method or all lines in the method.
当我们完成方法中的所有语句或者全部方法
Or when we've reached the first return statement, whichever one comes first.
或者方法执行的过程中遇到第一个 return 语句 无论哪个先发生
A method will also end if we've thrown an exception or
一个方法都结束了如果我们抛出异常或
an error, but we're not going to cover that in this course.
错误 不过我们这节课不讲
We're mostly going to focus on the first two cases.
这里我们主要讲解前两种情况
So in the code, you might see something like return semicolon.
所以在代码 你可能会看到 return 分号
That means the method should end and
这意味着方法结束
any line of code that comes after this won't be executed.
这之后的任何一行代码都不会执行
Alternatively you might see something like this.
作为选择你可以看看这个
Return and then a value, semi-colon.
return 加上一个值 然后分号
This is returning an output value from the method.
这是方法的返回值
Here's an example.
这有一个例子
This is code for the getArea method.
这是 getArea 方法的代码
It's supposed to compute the area of a rectangle,
这个方法用于计算矩形面积
which is defined as width times height.
就是长乘以宽的值
So inside the method we have the word return followed by the return value.
所以在方法内部我们在 return 后加上了返回值
The return value is the variable width times the variable height.
返回值是变量 width 乘以变量 height
And this equals a single number.
它只是一个数字
And that number is returned as the output value for this method.
这个数字会作为返回值输出
Unlike input parameters,
不同于输入参数
where you can has any many input parameters listed inbetween
你可以列出很多输入参数在
the opening the closing parentheses, you can only have a single return value.
左右括号之中 你只能有一个返回值
And the data type of that return value is specified here.
而且方法的返回值的类型是指定的
So we could have returned any other number, as long as it's an integer.
所以我们可以返回任何数 只要是整型
For example, you can't return a string,
例如 你不可以返回字符串
because that doesn't match the entered data type.
因为这与输入数据的类型不匹配
You're probably realizing by now that Java has a special meaning for
你也许发现 Java 对于return
the word return.
有特殊意义
You can't use it for the name of variables or methods.
你不能用它命名变量或方法
These are called Java key words.
这叫 Java 关键词
I can search for the Java keywords list.
我可以查找 Java 关键词列表
This is the list of all the Java keywords.
这是所有 Java 关键词的列表
You'll notice that some of the words we've already seen before,
你会发现这里的词我们之前看到过
like int, public, and private.
比如 int public 和 private
It's a pretty short list.
那是一个相当简短的表
And all these words have a special meaning in Java when you put them
在 Java 中所有这些词都有特殊的含义当你把它们放到
in your code.
你的代码中
So that means you can't use them for identifiers, like variable names, or
你就不能把它们用作标识符 比如变量名
method names in your app.
你应用的方法名
And you'll also notice that return is a special Java keyword.
你会发现 return 同样是个特殊的 Java 关键字
This is reserved for when you want to return an output value from a method.
这个词仅用于你需要为方法返回值的时候64
Going back to our earlier example of creating a weather message.
回到我们早前创建的天气消息的例子
We can create a string and then return it by saying return message.
我们可以创建一个字符串并通过 return message返回它
The data type of this variable is string.
这个变量的数据类型是字符串型
What would happen if I added a line of code after this return statement?
如果在返回值语句后面加一行会发生什么
Well then I would get an error that says unreachable statement.
好吧我将得到一个错误显示无法执行的代码
Because the computer won't get to these lines of code
因为在 return 语句后 计算机不能运行到
after the return statement.
这行代码
because it would have ended the method at this point.
因为它在这一点上已经将方法结束了
So delete any lines of code that come after your return statement.
所以将 return 语句后面的任何代码都删除
What if you don't need your method to return any output value?
如果你的方法不需要返回任何值会怎样？
Well let's look at a couple of examples in the MainActivity
让我们来看两个例子
of the JustJava app App.
在 JustJava app 应用的 MainActivity 中
The increment and decrement methods are examples where there is no return value.
Increment 和 decrement 的方法是没有返回值的例子
When you call the decrement method,
当我们调用 decrement 方法
it does all of its hard work in updating the UI in the displayQuantity method.
它的所有工作集中在更新 displayQuantity 方法的UI
There's no output value to return.
这里没有输出的返回值
And same with the increment method, all the hard work is done
increment 方法也一样 工作重点在
when you call displayQuantity and it updates the screen.
当你调用 displayQuantity 并更新屏幕
You might be wondering where the return statement is, then.
你可能对 return 语句感到疑惑 之后
Well, the method will finish executing when all the lines of code have been
所有的代码都完成这个方法就结束执行了
completed, or when it hits the return statement.
或者当它运行 return 语句的时候
So, I could've added return; like this.
所以 我不能像这样添加 return;
That way, the method would finish as soon as it hits this line.
这种方法 当运行到这一行方法就结束了
This gives me a warning in Android Studio.
Android Studio 会报错
It says, return is unnecessary at the last statement in Avoid method.
它说 在 void 方法最后一行语句的 return 是不必要的
Since I'm not returning anything, I can just delete this line here.
因为我不需要返回任何东西 我可以删掉这一行
This is less lines of code and its easier to read, so
这使代码更简短和容易阅读
I prefer it like this.
我更倾向于它这样
To indicate that there is no return value, It's important in the method
指出 这里是没有返回值的 在方法中声明
signature to say that the return data type is void.
返回数据类型是 void 很重要
Void just means that there's no return value.
void 意味着这里没有返回值
Java has a special way of representing this, so
Java 表达这些有特殊的方式
that's why this is a Java keyword.
这就是为什么这是一个 Java 关键字
Let's look back at our Java keyword list and, indeed,
让我们回过头看看我们的 Java 关键字列表
we see that void is in this list.
void 真的在表里面
So, if you don't have a return value,
如果你不需要返回值
make sure you don't just leave it blank like this.
确定你这里没有空白
because otherwise there's a java syntax error.
否则这会产生 Java 语法错误
Just type void with a lower case V.
只需要将 void 的 v 小写
Go ahead and read this article on your own now.
继续看你自己的文章
You can skim it for the information you do understand, or Google search for
你可以看你懂得的知识 或用 Google 查找
more information online.
更多网上的知识
Once you've learned a couple of things from this article,
一旦你学会了文章中的知识
you can move on to the task.
你可以练习一下
And then check your notes.
并勾选你的笔记
You'll find the link to some code for four different methods.
你会发现四个不同方法的代码的链接
Each method contains an error.
每个方法都有一个错误
And the task is for you to find the error in each of these methods.
这个练习是让你找出每个方法的错误
Since there's multiple ways to fix the code,
这有多种修改代码的方法
assume that the javadoc comment at the top of each method is correct.
假设每个方法上面的注释都是正确的
And we want to make the code match that.
我们想要使代码匹配它
This is what the methods look like.
这就是方法的样子
Identify the line number that the error is on.
确定错误出现在第几行
The line number is located in the left-hand column here.
行数在左手边的栏上
Then write a short description on why that line has an error.
之后写一个简短的注释为什么这一行错了
So line number goes here, and description goes here.
所以行数在这 描述在这
When you're done, you can continue to the solution video.
当你这么做了 你可以继续解决方法的视频